[FERN] I have a teacher,
and it's Mistress Frieren.
-[SERIE] You pass.
-[yawning]
[SERIE] Next.
You're
a
breeze
blow
ing
through
When
you
close
your
eyes,
sun
light
starts
to
fade
tell
what
you
might
be
thin
king
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
Once
your
eyes
once
a
gain
are
o
pen
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
P3cmCn8aUpUoDQ
!wkQ'e9nQu64r
AN AGELESS ELEGY
zing
out
a
head,
clear
as
orbs
of
glass
Some
where
deep
wi
thin,
I
can
sense
the
clouds
clea
ring
blue
reign
and
ba
nish
the
gray
Buds
are
bloo
ming
storms
will
calm
as
the
fog
rolls
wer's
mist
I'll
take
con
trol
of
this
bea
ting
wi
thin
boku
We'll
be
one
with
the
wind
Let's
reach
the
clouds
yond
ring
end
less
ly
in
to
the
dawn
[SERIE]
Denken the Imperial Mage.
I know all about you.
I am honored to hear it,
Mistress Serie.
[SERIE] A self-made man who got
his start in the military,
then rose to be
the most influential mage
in all the northern lands.
You're the subject
of many an inspiring tale.
To tell you the truth,
I wish that I'd met you
when you were still young.
Still full of energy
and ambition,
your passion burning bright.
[water splattering]
I have no interest
in a great flame's cinders.
At least that's
what I believed.
And do you believe
differently, now?
Perhaps.
When you first walked in,
you considered how
you would fight me.
[DENKEN] I did,
but only for a moment.
I quickly abandoned that idea.
The fire remains.
And so, you pass.
Most people
are too afraid to fight me
even in their heads.
Next.
♪
You've passed the test.
Hm? I'm pretty sure
interviews require words.
[SERIE] Were you hoping
for conversation?
[chuckles]
I know when to quit.
Next.
♪
Young man, is this a joke?
Pardon?
You're taking
the first-class mage exam.
You really couldn't be
bothered to set foot
on the testing grounds?
As you can see,
the real me has made
an appearance
in case that is a requirement
for passing.
I'm not so easily deceived.
Your actual body
never left your hometown.
I hope you're enjoying
that cup of tea.
♪
How impressive.
Not even Übel realized it.
You have tremendous nerve.
You pass.
Next.
♪
[SERIE] You're Wirbel,
captain of
the Northern Magic Corps.
Of all the second-class mages
I know,
you are by far
the most skilled in combat.
[chuckles]
[SERIE] In a single look,
you realized a battle
with me would be pointless.
But that wasn't a judgment
made out of fear.
If I were the type
to pick fights I can't win,
I wouldn't have even
made it to second class.
That's a good point.
What's your favorite spell?
[WIRBEL] Spells aren't to be
liked or disliked.
Magic's a tool for killing.
[chuckles]
You have passed.
Next.
♪
Tell me.
What did you think
when you saw me?
[gasps]
[METHODE] Well, um,
I thought you were very small
and very adorable?
[SERIE] This year's test-takers
are a different breed
all together.
[SERIE] You pass.
[door opens]
Sense.
My apologies.
It does seem
we have a bumper crop.
[SCHARF] I failed.
Always next time, champ.
[LAND] Stop following
me around.
A whole three years, huh?
I passed the test,
Mistress Frieren.
[chuckles]
Excellent job.
Frieren.
Who knows how far
I would've made it
without you and your protege.
Thanks to you,
I can finally visit
a certain grave up north.
Good.
[STARK]
Come on, Fern.
You gotta pick something.
[FERN] Hmm?
[FERN] I think I'd like--
[LAUFEN] I want these, Grandpa.
-Hm.
[chuckles]
♪
Eat up, everyone.
Don't be shy.
When I was a lad,
I never got to indulge
in sweet treats like these.
Thank you very much, sir.
♪
[STARK] Am I missing something?
Have a few, young man.
Right.
Appreciate it, old-timer.
♪
[STARK] Who's he?
That's Mister Denken.
He's an Imperial Mage.
Hm. Well, that sounds
awfully fancy.
♪
[gasps] Huh.
You mean
the old timer's a noble?
Oopsie.
I'm sorry for speaking
to you so casually.
Don't worry yourself.
I came to this city as a mage
just like any other.
[STARK] Sure, but you shouldn't
feel obliged
to treat a stranger like me.
Oh, please. I have no
better use for my money.
Come on,
that can't be the truth.
He's right. No family?
[DENKEN] Hm?
I wasn't blessed with
children or grandchildren.
My wife passed away
when I was in my mid-twenties.
The poor girl was sickly
from the day we met.
Her father
was a frontier noble
of the Northern Plateau
and had been defeated
in a political dispute.
Back in those days,
wealth and influence
were two things
I desperately lacked.
They also seemed
to be the only mechanisms
by which I could save her.
Soon, Serie established
the Continental
Magic Association
and began offering
the privilege.
But it was too late.
My wife had just passed.
I had never felt
so powerless in my life.
And now I have
all the power in the world.
If only I could have been
for my beloved then
who I have become today.
-[DENKEN] Fern.
-Hm.
In my life,
magic was reduced to a tool
for resolving
political disputes.
There is something I'd like
you to tell your master.
That I had long forgotten
how joyful magic can be,
but she gave me
a firm reminder.
I've admired Frieren's deeds
in the party of heroes
since I was a boy.
I credit her
with my becoming a mage.
Hm.
You should tell her
that yourself.
I'm certain she would
be happy to hear it.
Perhaps you're right.
I'll do that.
[indistinct chatter]
The magical city of Äußerst
did not disappoint.
I found some
top-notch grimoires.
-[clattering]
-Hm.
[WIRBEL] Allow me.
You want them
in the basket, right?
[clattering]
You would ignore the poor lady?
Helping her did cross
my mind for a moment.
Just a moment, huh?
I'm surprised at you.
I thought you were a member
of Himmel's party.
You think there's a certain way
I should act, yes?
Your actions have been
more surprising than mine.
I heard that you tried
to kill Fern's party
during the first test.
Fern was quite upset.
She said you'd kick a puppy
if it was in your way.
[chuckles]
Many folks would agree.
All I did was threaten them.
Though looking back, if I
had taken one of those lives,
I might've been doing
the world a favor.
There's no one I wouldn't kill
to protect my village
and the people in it.
The whole reason
I'm here is the privilege.
I want to get my hands on
the most powerful spell I can.
The demons already thought
I was a force
to be reckoned with,
but they haven't seen
anything yet.
I protect, but I also try
to help when I can.
Any place and anybody.
My goal is to lighten the load
of people in need.
[FRIEREN]
Why's that?
Like countless others
born on the northern frontier,
my childhood was dominated
by tales of Himmel the Hero.
The conquest
of the Thousand-Mirror Tower.
His battles against Bose
the Immortal.
And the Hell Emperor Dragon.
As a kid, I would sink my teeth
into every adventure story
that made it my way.
But the village elders
were never as interested
in those stories
of swords as I was.
They'd talk about
how he defeated
the monsters that
attacked the village,
or how he once guarded
some merchant,
or how he helped
little old ladies
carry their groceries.
Those tales were
nothing significant.
Just boring favors.
That's what I thought, anyway.
But when the elders
shared them,
their eyes lit up bright,
as thrilled
by these small deeds
as I was by the great ones.
After Himmel the Hero died
and the remaining demons
started acting up,
that's when
I finally understood.
♪
[WIRBEL] Sure enough,
the Thousand-Mirror Tower,
Bose, the Hell Emperor Dragon,
even the Demon King?
None of them meant
as much as home.
And home keeps
your hands too full
to worry about
that kind of stuff.
Thing is, if Himmel the Hero
hadn't visited my village,
I doubt that my home
would still be around,
whether he had
saved the world or not.
Right.
And all that to say?
That the small stuff
counts just as much!
Himmel's less-exciting
adventures
are what guided me here.
♪
[WIRBEL] It's really
nothing that complex.
♪
[WIRBEL] Guess I've been
chatting for too long.
My party's ready
to hit the road,
and they look impatient.
Frieren.
Always treasure
the people you meet.
Death is far from this
lifetime's only goodbye.
♪
Then again,
I don't have to tell you that.
♪
[sheep bleating]
Frieren. If we go one by one,
isn't there some way you could
magic each of us across?
Possibly, but then I'd be left
all alone on this side.
[EISEN] Himmel.
We should waste no time
in defeating the Demon King.
What point is there
in helping people
in such insignificant ways?
[chuckles]
[HIMMEL] They are
insignificant, I suppose.
Deeds like these
will not change lives,
let alone the world.
But people need help,
and I cannot turn my back
on those right in front of me.
♪
[thuds]
[FRIEREN] Don't worry, Himmel.
It turns out the world
was changed after all.
[FERN] We're going to be
granted our privileges tonight,
and apparently, we're each
allowed to bring guests.
It's once in a lifetime.
So we should all go.
-Hm.
-Hm?
[FERN] Goodness,
Mistress Frieren,
don't look so excited.
Huh? But I was told we were
allowed to bring guests.
I'm terribly sorry, ma'am,
but Miss Frieren
has been banned.
Mistress Serie's orders.
She's barred from all
Continental Magic
Association facilities
for the next 1000 years.
That's quite a steep punishment
when there wasn't a crime.
It can't be helped.
I've gotten on her bad side,
and that's where I'll stay.
Serie is truly
the world's oldest child.
It's not as if I came here
of my own accord, anyway.
I shall wait outside.
♪
I may as well give her
some company.
Hey!
♪
[bell rings]
That's the evening bell.
They'll be done receiving
their privileges before long.
Yeah.
She's a first-class mage now.
That's a pinnacle
not even 50 mages
in the whole world
have reached.
Young Fern has grown so much.
I have no doubt, in this era,
Fern will become a mage
even more famous than me.
[STARK] Frieren.
That's a good thing.
[chuckles] I agree.
-[LERNEN] Miss Frieren.
-Hm.
Who's he?
He's one
of the Magic Association's men.
My name is Lernen,
and I'm a first class-mage.
A longtime student
of Mistress Serie.
I am sorry for the trouble
my mistress has caused you.
No worries there.
She has behaved
just as I expected.
Hm.
Is something wrong, Frieren?
[FRIEREN] The way
you're looking at me.
You see the fluctuations
in my mana.
You are tremendously skilled,
but this peaceful era
doesn't suit you, does it?
[LERNEN] Not in the slightest.
I am an old-fashioned mage
who knows painfully little
outside the realm of battle.
Mistress Serie
often says the same.
If only I'd been
born in the height
of the Demon King's reign,
my name would've been
written in history
alongside the names of the rest
of you famous heroes.
Perhaps.
So what is it you want
from me, then?
Out of all
Mistress Serie's students,
there's only one
remembered today.
Her very first apprentice,
the legendary
Great Mage Flamme.
It's no secret I am soon
to return to dust,
and when I die,
so will some proof
of my mistress's existence.
I don't want her
to be alone in the future.
So, I'll leave a legacy
to keep her company.
Infamy must suffice,
as being the mage
who killed
the legendary Frieren
won't illicit kind remarks
from generations to come.
♪
[shattering]
[LERNEN] I request a duel,
-Miss Frieren.
-[grunts]
[FRIEREN] I am not
going to fight you.
It's a waste of time.
What a bother.
Mages who only know
how to fight
are simply horrid
at the softer things.
There's really no need
for history to remember you.
Serie will do
a fine job of that.
♪
One thing before I go.
That small field of flowers
was conjured by magic.
Yes, and your point is?
That you used
my master's favorite spell.
You told me that you
found it foolish and useless.
♪
I am not one to mince words.
Flamme was a failure.
Despite her immense talent,
she never reached my heights.
I've taken on
many apprentices since,
most of whom
followed a similar,
disappointing trajectory.
The failures that they were?
I remember each and every one.
I always choose
my students on a whim,
yet their personalities
and favorite spells
are carved into my mind.
Frieren.
As pitiful as most
proved to be,
I've never regretted
taking them on.
Even if they didn't become
the legends I foresaw.
[FRIEREN] It's a pity
she can't tell her own students
how she truly feels.
She's ever the child
I thought she was.
Hm. Mistress Frieren!
I'm all done
receiving my privilege.
Let's be off, then.
[FERN] Goodness.
How did you get
that wound on your shoulder?
All that matters now
is getting it healed.
Do you think there are
any churches open?
We are horrid at
the softer things, aren't we?
[LERNEN] That is true
of the both of us.
-[all chuckle]
-Mister Stark!
-What's today's mission?
-[ALL] Huh?
[STARK] Sorry, kiddos.
I'm afraid
I can't play this time.
Hey, Stark!
How 'bout some breakfast
on the house?
Thanks, but I already ate.
Mister Stark! Would you
like something to drink?
[STARK] Sure, thank you.
The path of the warrior is
a long and treacherous one.
Walk it with care.
Right.
♪
[FRIEREN] It's time to say
goodbye to Äußerst.
Wow, Mister Stark.
People love you
everywhere you go.
Think so?
By the way, Fern.
What spell did you
end up asking for?
Hm.
What, can you not tell?
Your clothes are so clean
they look new.
[sniffs]
And there's a vaguely
floral smell about them.
I can't believe it.
It's a spell that
removes stains
and cleans clothes
down to the stitch.
It's going to make doing
laundry a breeze.
So, Serie is a living grimoire
after all, then.
You've won a legendary-level
cleaning spell
from the era of mythology.
Superb choice, Fern.
[excited]
There is no doubt
you're my apprentice.
♪
That's for sure.
Not one bit.
Mistress Serie didn't seem
quite as happy
with my selection, though.
Are you out of your mind?
[FRIEREN] I believe it.
Serves her right.
[KANNE] Oh! They're here.
Frieren!
We just wanted
to say thank you.
We may not have been
fully prepared
this time around,
but we have three years
to train for the next one.
Sure. Good to hear.
Thanks for the fun.
Safe travels.
[FRIEREN]
I'll see you later.
[KANNE]
Right. See you!
♪
[FERN] You kept that farewell
rather short and simple,
just like you did with Sein.
[STARK] And with Kraft.
♪
[FRIEREN] It's funny, Himmel.
You always bid
such quick goodbyes.
And that's strange?
[EISEN] Eh, it's more like
a break in character.
It may have just
been a side job,
but we spent two weeks
traveling with him.
[HEITER] Think of all
the laughs we shared.
We drank with the fellow
practically every night.
-[FRIEREN] You corrupt priest.
-[chuckles] You have a point.
But I'm not retiring soon,
and I'm sure
our paths will cross
somewhere down the line.
I don't think
a tearful farewell
would suit us anyway.
And besides,
it would be embarrassing
when we met again.
[chuckles]
It would be embarrassing
when we met again.
[STARK] Huh?
[FERN] Huh?
[FERN] What is that
supposed to mean?
Episode 28: It Would Be Embarrassing the Next Time We Met